A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 6262-9286 FA739C
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Can we afford a half-time university? (Reports 007269), 1976 (Box 319)
  Universities and colleges -- Pakistan; College attendance -- Pakistan; Akhtar, Humaira; Currimbhoy, Azizeh; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Shaikh, Sayeed A.; University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre
- Wheat marketing in Pakistan: an appraisal of prospects and requirements (Reports 007270), 1969 (Box 319)
  Prepared for the Secretary, Planning Commission, Pakistan Secretariat. Observations during a one month visit of wheat producing regions and marketing facilities in West Pakistan.
  Wheat -- Marketing -- Pakistan; Madill, J. Wallace
- Some programmatic implications of women's reproductive health needs in rural Pakistan (Reports 007271), 1977 (Box 319)
  Initial analysis of the health needs of rural women, suggestions on how health care workers can expand their services, and how do constraints of the purdah system affect rural women's health care-seeking behavior and participation in social and economic d
  21 p. + appendices.
  Rural women -- Health and hygiene -- Pakistan; Reproductive health -- Pakistan; Mayo, Molly R.
- Refugees and migrants: problems and program responses, June 1983. (Reports 007272) (Box 319)
  Prepared for a June 1983 Board of Trustees meeting, "a discussion of the problems posed and experienced by refugees and migrants around the world....and of current and future grant activity within the 3 Foundation programs now most actively engaged in the
  United States and International Affairs Program/Urban Poverty program/Human Rights and Governance/International Affairs
  Refugees; Emigration and immigration; Migration, Internal
- Pakistan visit to Indus Basin: July 2-9 (Reports 007273), 1977 (Box 319)
  Memo to Peter Hakim and John Cool, dated July 8, 1977.
  Watersheds -- Research -- Pakistan; Watershed management -- Pakistan; Groundwater -- Pakistan; Levine, Gilbert, 1948-; Ford Foundation. India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
- Some cultural elements of family planning practices: bleeding disturbances and contraceptive method (Reports 007274), 1976 (Box 319)
  Discussion of the need to address side effects, especially abnormal bleeding, which cause women to stop using their birth control methods, which leads to unwanted pregnancies. The bothersome bleeding is associated with the menstrual taboos in many societi
  22 p. + appendices.
  Oral contraceptives -- Side effects; Birth control; Menstruation -- Cross-cultural studies; Mayo, Molly R.
- Feminism and family planning policies: observations on Pakistan-India-Bangladesh (Reports 007275), 1976 (Box 319)
  Discussion on the conditions of women in Asian countries and their role in development and population.
  Women in development -- Pakistan; Women in development -- India; Women in development -- Bangladesh; Birth control -- Pakistan; Birth control -- India; Birth control -- Bangladesh; Mayo, Molly R.; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Women in their society: a selected bibliography of Pakistan and other Islamic countries (Reports 007276), 1976 (Box 319)
  Attempts to define, provide a frame of reference for, and give order and structure to existing body of literature on women, attempt to establish a basic tool of research required to validate the study of women as a legitimate scholarly pursuit, and identi
  Women -- Pakistan; Women -- Islamic countries; Muslim women -- Pakistan; Muslim women; Mayo, Molly R.
- Annual technical report: accelerated wheat improvement program, West Pakistan, 1967-68 (Reports 007277), 1968 (Box 319)
  Prepared for the Secretary of Agriculture, Government of West Pakistan. Discussion of the progress made on improving wheat crops in Pakistan.
  123 p. + appendices.
  Wheat -- Pakistan; Munshi, M. Z. A. (M. Zafar A.); Abdulaziz, Mohamed Hassan; Khan, M. Suleyman; Qureshi, S. A.; Narvaez Morales, Ignacio
- Fourth annual technical report: accelerated wheat improvement program, West Pakistan 1968-69 (Reports 007278), 1969 (Box 319)
  Prepared for Secretary of Agriculture, Govt. of West Pakistan. Review of wheat crops in Pakistan.
  109 p. + appendices.
  Wheat -- Pakistan; Munshi, M. Z. A. (M. Zafar A.); Hassan, M. M.; Saeed, Mohammad; Bajwa, Manzoor A.; Qureshi, S. A.; Narvaez Morales, Ignacio
- Observations regarding the Population Planning Council's proposed training program for family welfare supervisors (Reports 007279), 1976 (Box 319)
  Evaluation of the training program in Pakistan.
  Family services -- Pakistan; Minkler, Meredith
- West Pakistan's Rice Improvement Program (Reports 007280), 1968 (Box 319)
  Discusses limitations in West Pakistan's rice production and suggestions for improvement.
  Rice -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Mueller, Kenneth E.
- Rice stem borer - 1970; and Rice stem borer- short course (Reports 007281) (Box 319)
  Analysis of the causes of the stem borer outbreak in the rice crop of 1970.
  Stem borers -- Pakistan -- Punjab (India); Rice -- Diseases and pests -- Pakistan -- Punjab (India); McLean, Gordon W.; Koehler, Carlton S.
- The determinants of mortality in a low income area of Karachi (Reports 007282), 1979 (Box 319)
  A study of the factors which affect mortality rates in developing countries.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 35
  Mortality -- Developing countries; Knowles, James C.
- The pros and cons of exchange control in developing countries (Reports 007283), 1975 (Box 319)
  Based on the last part of the author's paper: Marginalist economic theory and public policy. Checklist to help policymakers weigh the pros and cons of a wide variety of economic decisions and how it applies to exchange controls in developing countries.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 5
  Foreign exchange -- Law and legislation -- Developing countries; Klitgaard, Robert E.
- Regression without a model: analyzing school efficiency in Karachi (Reports 007284), 1978 (Box 319)
  Study of how education policy impacts examination scores.
  Education and state -- Pakistan; Education -- Pakistan; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Dadabhoy, Sadequa; Litkouhi, Simin
- Efficiency and equity in secondary schools in Karachi: summary (Reports 007285), 1977 (Box 319)
  Study based on stratified sample of Karachi's secondary schools to analyze educational efficiency and equity.
  Research report (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 10
  Educational equalization -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Education -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Dadabhoy, Sadequa; Litkouhi, Simin
- Do schools care about equality? (Reports 007286), 1977 (Box 319)
  Based on an empirical study of the distribution of examination scores within secondary schools in Karachi. It is argued that schools do not care about the equality of their students' educational achievements.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 17
  Educational equalization -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Dadabhoy, Sadequa; Litkouhi, Simin
- Inflation in university grades: an example from Pakistan (Reports 007287), 1977 (Box 319)
  Study of the rise in grades at Karachi University.
  Grading and marking (Students) -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Currimbhoy, Azizeh; University Of Karachi
- Exploring the neglected: A study of fruit and vegetable hawkers in Karachi (Reports 007288), 1977 (Box 319)
  Study of the informal sector in the cities of developing countries, focusing on Karachi.
  Research report (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 4
  Informal sector (Economics) -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Poor -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Hafeez, Sabeeha; Zahid, Shahid N.; Akhtar, Aasim Sajjad; Hakeem, Safia
- Choosing the elite: A study of admissions policy for higher education: Summary (Reports 007289), 1977 (Box 319)
  Description of admissions policy to colleges and universities in Pakistan, which reveals that the current criteria of admission have little predictive power for university or professional school performance.
  Research report (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 7
  Universities and colleges -- Pakistan -- Admission; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Akbar, Fatima; Hakeem, Safia; Raffi, Rabia; Tazeem-ur-Rehman
- The economics of teacher training: summary (Reports 007290), 1977 (Box 320)
  Study of teacher training institutions in Pakistan.
  Research report (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 8
  Teachers -- Training of -- Pakistan; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Siddiqui, Khalil Y.; Arshad, Mohammed; Niaz, Naheed; Khan, Muneer A.
- Statistical analysis and improved policy-making (Reports 007291), 1976 (Box 320)
  Prepared for the Agriculture Research Council's Workshop on Economic Survey Studies, December 1976. Preliminary results of a research project being jointly conducted by the Applied Economics Research Centre at the University of Karachi and the Planning Un
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 14
  Wheat -- Pakistan; Cotton -- Pakistan; Wallace, Michael B.; Hasan, M. Aynul; Mahmud, Fakhre
- Preliminary findings from the Karachi Secondary School Study (Reports 007292), 1976 (Box 320)
  Research report;no. 3.
  Education, Secondary -- Research -- Pakistan; Educational evaluation -- Pakistan; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Dadabhoy, Sadequa; Litkouhi, Simin; Ford Foundation. Asia and the Pacific
- Egghead economics and practical policies (Reports 007293), 1976 (Box 320)
  Text of a talk given at the Management Association of Pakistan, August 1976. Discussion of the application of microeconomic theory to public policy, as in decisions of pricing publicly produced goods or in setting taxes or tariffs.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 13
  Economic policy; Economics -- Pakistan; Klitgaard, Robert E.
- Thought for food: improving analysis in the Ministry of Agriculture (Reports 007294), 1976 (Box 320)
  Prepared for the Ministry of Food and Agriculture, Govt. of Pakistan. Suggestions for improved economic and statistical analysis within the Ministry of Food and Agriculture.
  33 p. + appendices.
  Research report(University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 2
  Pakistan; Pakistan -- Economic conditions -- Statistics; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Pakistan. Ministry of Food, Agriculture & Cooperatives
- Cognitive equality within schools: an example from Pakistan (Reports 007295), 1978 (Box 320)
  An empirical study of distributions of examination scores within secondary schools in Karachi shows that intraschool inequalities are relatively large. The results of several analyses are consistent with the hypothesis that either schools in Karachi do no
  Education -- Aims and objectives -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Educational equalization -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Educational tests and measurements -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Klitgaard, Robert E.; Dadabhoy, Sadequa; Litkouhi, Simin
- Looking for the best: identifying exceptional performers in education and elsewhere (Reports 007296), 1975 (Box 320)
  Discussion of why exceptional performers should be identified and methods of finding them.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 6
  Successful people -- Pakistan; Education -- Pakistan; Klitgaard, Robert E.
- Student merit and admission policy for pharmacy school (Reports 007297), 1975 (Box 320)
  Study over the use of "merit" in university admissions using the School of Pharmacy as an example. The issue of who and who is not admitted to professional programs will have significant impact on Pakistan's manpower policies.
  Universities and colleges -- Pakistan -- Karachi -- Admissions; Pharmacy colleges -- Pakistan -- Karachi; Klitgaard, Robert E.; University of Karachi
- Marginalist economic theory and public policy (Reports 007298), 1975 (Box 320)
  Outline of the attractions and pitfalls of marginalist economic prescriptions. Includes discussion of NASA's pricing policies.
  95 p.
  Austrian school of economics; Economics; Klitgaard, Robert E.
- Determinants of the length of life in Asian, African and Latin American countries (Reports 007299), 1976 (Box 320)
  Study examining 71 developing countries of Asia, Africa, and Latin America to see whether the life expectancy in these countries can be predicted with the help of per caput GNP, daily per caput consumption of calories, population density, degree of urbani
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 9
  Life expectancy -- Developing countries; Dadabhoy, Sadequa
- Preliminary report of the diffusion and adoption of dwarf wheat varieties in Khanewal Tehsil, West Pakistan 1970 (Reports 007300) (Box 320)
  Wheat -- Varieties -- Pakistan; Lowdermilk, Max K.
- Preliminary thinking on the Agriculture Sector West Pakistan in the fourth Five-Year Plan (Reports 007301), 1968 (Box 320)
  Purpose of paper is to help improve the planning work of the Department. Outline of principles of agricultural programming and logical steps to be taken in the preparation of an agricultural development program for the Fourth Five-Year Plan.
  72 p.
  Agriculture -- Pakistan; Planning -- Pakistan; Aresvik, Oddvar, 1915-
- The role of agricultural education and research in the development of agriculture (Reports 007302), 1968 (Box 320)
  Prepared for a seminar on "Prospects and problems of agricultural development in Pakistan", April 23-24, 1968. Discusses the upcoming rural revolution and the importance of moving farmers into the age of science and technology.
  Agriculture -- Pakistan; Agricultural development projects -- Pakistan; Aresvik, Oddvar, 1915-
- Strategy and outlook for agricultural development in Pakistan, March 16 (Reports 007303), 1968 (Box 320)
  Prepared for a seminar on agricultural development in Lahore - March 16, 1968.
  Agricultural development projects -- Pakistan; Aresvik, Oddvar, 1915-
- Women's programs in Nicaragua (Reports 007304), 1979 (Box 320)
  Memo to the staff of the FF Women's Program in Central America, dated December 9, 1979.
  Women -- Services for -- Nicaragua; Redclift, Nanneke; Ford Foundation. Latin America and the Caribbean
- Report of the Subcommittee on the dynamics of telecommunications of the Telecommunications Task Force (Reports 007305), 1973 (Box 320)
  07290319
  Task force to determine Ford Foundation policy in telecommunications.
  Telecommunication -- United States; Mass media -- United States; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- The Telecommunications Task Force (Reports 007306), 1973 (Box 320)
  33 p. -- 28 cm.
  Telecommunication -- United States; Mass media -- United States; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting
- The computer-based education network: A geographically dispersed system for interactive self-paced learning (Reports 007307), 1973 (Box 320)
  A task force to determine Ford Foundation policy in telecommunications.
  var. pag. -- 28 cm.
  Computer-assisted instruction -- United States; Educational technology -- United States; Education -- United States; Computer systems -- Instruction and study -- United States; Alpert, Daniel (Economist); Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Television, political processes, and cultural behavior (Reports 007308), 1972 (Box 320)
  Television and politics -- United States; Television -- Research -- United States; Political campaigns -- United States; Mass media -- Research -- United States; Chu, Godwin C., 1927-; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- The open university concept in the U.S.A.: possibilities, obstacles, strategies (Reports 007309), 1973 (Box 320)
  Education, Higher -- United States; Education, Higher -- United Kingdom; Adult education -- United States; Adult education -- United Kingdom; Mass media -- Research -- United States; Hooper, Richard, 1821-1894
- Communications and society: suggestions for research and inquiry (Reports 007310), 1973 (Box 320)
  Communication -- Social aspects -- United States; Telecommunication systems -- United States; Mass media -- Research -- United States; Kaufman, Paul, 1935-; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Television: what new forms of international cooperation might be useful? (Reports 007311), 1974 (Box 320)
  Television -- International cooperation; Television -- Developing countries; Communication -- Research -- Developing countries; Mass media -- Research -- Developing countries; Kohl, Kay Jordan, 1940-; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- On the use of telecommunications to meet the educational needs of developing nations (Reports 007312), 1973 (Box 320)
  Report to the Subcommittee on Education and Telecommunications, Division of Education & Research, dated March 31, 1973.
  77 p. -- 28 cm.
  Television -- International cooperation; Television -- Developing countries; Mass media -- Research -- Developing countries; Margolin, Joseph B., 1921-2006; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Possible uses of telecommunications to meet the educational needs of women (Reports 007313), 1973 (Box 320)
  Television and women; Television in adult education; Mass media -- Research; Sandler, Jerrold; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Possible uses of telecommunications to meet the educational needs of the aging (Reports 007314), 1973 (Box 320)
  Mass media and older people; Television in adult education; Mass media -- Research; Sandler, Jerrold; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Education, technology, and development: a critical reappraisal (Reports 007315), 1973 (Box 320)
  Educational technology -- Developing countries; Mass media in education -- Developing countries; Mass media -- Research -- Developing countries; Sheffield, James R.; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Creativity-problem solving-education-television-television-education-problem solving-creativity-problem solving-creativity-television-education-education-television-creativity-problem solving-creativity-solving-television-education problem: some why's s (Reports 007316), 1973 (Box 320)
  A paper prepared for the Telecommunication Task Force Subcommittee on Education of the Ford Foundation.
  8 p.: ill. -- 28 cm.
  Television in education; Television and the arts; Mass media -- Research; Watson, William; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- Why the arts? (Reports 007317), 1973 (Box 321)
  Television and the arts; Mass media -- Research; Watson, William; Ford Foundation. Public Broadcasting; Ford Foundation. Humanities and the Arts; Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
- The elasticity of income taxes in Pakistan: an alternative approach (Reports 007318), 1978 (Box 321)
  Discussion of taxation in Pakistan.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 25
  Income tax -- Pakistan; Jeetun, Azad
- Commercial banks' profitability and portfolio structuring in Pakistan 1960-71 (Reports 007319), 1975 (Box 321)
  Discussion of the growth of banking in Pakistan as part of economic development.
  Banks and banking -- Pakistan; Siddiqui, Q. H.
- Current plans for the development of computing facilities and computer science at the University of Islamabad final version (Reports 007320), 1969 (Box 321)
  Recommendations for a new computer facility at the University of Islamabad and a supporting program in computer science.
  46 p. -- 28 cm.
  Computer laboratories -- Pakistan -- Islamabad; Computer science -- Pakistan -- Islamabad; Hagstrom, Stanley; University of Islamabad Computers; University of Islamabad Computer science
- Suggestions for further improvement in the accelerated potato improvement program in West Pakistan (Reports 007321), 1969 (Box 321)
  Prepared for the Secretary of Agriculture of the Government of West Pakistan. Overview of the accomplishments of the potato program.
  Potatoes -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Niederhauser, John S.; Campos, Armando
- The NWFP Maize Production Program (Reports 007322), 1972 (Box 321)
  Corn -- Yields -- Pakistan; Izuno, Takumi
- Asian population review Pakistan: Population situation and possible entry points for assistance (Reports 007323), 1972 (Box 321)
  Preliminary draft report, prepared during October 10-Nov. 10 1972. Pakistan situation discussed in terms of what is happening in population and what is needed that the Foundation can provide.
  Pakistan -- Population; Laurenti, Luigi
- Elasticity and buoyancy of excise duties and import duties: a disaggregated study (Reports 007324), 1978 (Box 321)
  Report of a recent study on import duties, excise duties, and sales taxes.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 26
  Excise tax -- Pakistan; Tariff -- Pakistan; Sales tax -- Pakistan; Jeetun, Azad
- Trends in inequality of income distribution in Pakistan (Reports 007325), 1978 (Box 321)
  Measures the trends in income inequalities in Pakistan to find out whether economic growth spurs greater inequality.
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 29
  Income distribution -- Pakistan; Jeetun, Azad
- The Federal tax system in Pakistan: an overview (Reports 007326), 1978 (Box 321)
  Broad picture of the changing composition of revenue during the period 1960-61 and 1977/78 focusing on a few basic characteristics of the tax system in Pakistan.
  Taxation -- Pakistan; Jeetun, Azad
- Tax shifting in Pakistan: a case study of excise duties, sales tax and import duties (Reports 007327), 1978 (Box 321)
  First section of analysis deals with the effect of changes in sales tax and excise duties on prices over the period 1963/64 to 1977/78, including surcharges. The second section presents findings on the impact of changes in import duties in January 1978 on
  Discussion paper (University of Karachi. Applied Economics Research Centre);no. 28
  Tax shifting -- Pakistan; Excise tax -- Pakistan; Sales tax -- Pakistan; Tariff -- Pakistan; Jeetun, Azad
- Multiple cropping patterns for the rice tract of Punjab, West Pakistan (Reports 007328), 1971 (Box 321)
  Discussion of multiple cropping for rice in Punjab, Pakistan.
  Rice -- Pakistan -- Punjab (India); Multiple cropping -- Pakistan -- Punjab (India); Khan, Muhammad Manzoor.
- Possibilities of adopting multiple cropping practices in Dokri, Sind (Reports 007329), 1971 (Box 321)
  Report submitted to the Rice Improvement Advisor and the Rice Botanist. Purpose of visit to the Government Rice Farm was to find out the possibilities of introducing a systematic multiple cropping scheme in the area in order to increase food production an
  Multiple cropping -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Food supply -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Nutrition -- Pakistan -- West Pakistan; Khan, Muhammad Manzoor.
- Possibilities of adopting multiple cropping practices in Peshawar, N.W.F.P. (Reports 007330), 1970 (Box 321)
  Report submitted to the Rice Improvement Advisor and the Director of Agriculture. Purpose of visit to Peshawar was to find out the possibilities of introducing a systematic multiple cropping scheme in the area in order to increase food production and impr
  Multiple cropping -- Pakistan -- North-west Frontier Province; Food supply -- Pakistan -- North-west Frontier Province; Nutrition -- Pakistan -- North-west Frontier Province; Khan, Muhammad Manzoor.
- Maize in Asian cropping systems: present positions and considerations for improvement (Reports 007331), 1975 (Box 321)